CS 1110 Extensions
Authors: Zain Khoja (znk4), Gracie Jing (kgj7)
Date: May 7, 2019


Multiple Waves
There are 3 waves per game. After each wave, the speed is changed to the original speed divided by the wave number (i.e. the third wave has a speed ALIEN_SPEED/3). I implemented this by creating a new global variable for speed that changed for and was passed to each new wave.

Sound Effects
Each action in the game has a sound effect. For the Ship and Alien objects, I created an instance attribute for each sound. I created methods to play each sound (and check if the game was muted or not) and called these methods when appropriate in the game. I have sounds for the Ship and Alien bolts and deaths.

Dynamically Speed Up the Aliens
The Aliens walking speed becomes 0.97 * the current speed after the Ship destroys an Alien. Similar to creating multiple waves, I used the global speed variable I created and reassigned the value after removing an alien.

Keep Track of Score
I keep track of the player's score in the top left. Alien 1s are worth 100 points, Alien 2s are worth 200 points, and Alien 3s are worth 300 points. I created a global score and and a global scoreLabel variable to update each time an Alien is killed.

Animate the Aliens
I implemented the Alien walking animation by changing my Image object for Aliens to GSprite objects and following the instructions to make the frames move.